Inventory of the Samuel Sokobin papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Samuel Sokobin papers
1904-1987
91047
Hoover Institution Archives
1 manuscript box, 1 oversize box (0.8 linear feet)
Writings relating to books written by Western travelers to China from the sixteenth century through the nineteenth century; and Chinese paintings, scrolls and engravings.
Sokobin, Samuel, 1893-
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1991.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
American consular official in China, 1914-1940; collector of rare books on China.
Scope and Content of Collection
Writings relating to books written by Western travelers to China from the sixteenth century through the nineteenth century; and Chinese paintings, scrolls and engravings.
Americans--China.; Art objects, Chinese.; China--Description and travel--Bibliography.; Europeans--China.; Paintings.; Scrolls, Chinese.
- Writings, 1980s
  - "Knee Breeches and Tricorns," reprinted article, 1987 (Box-folder 1: 1)
  - "Up and Down the China Coast," alternate title "Taipans and Gunboats; Diplomats and Missionaries," unpublished writings, 1980s (Box-folder 1: 2-10)
  - Holiday greeting cards, undated (Box-folder 1: 11)
- Paintings and Calligraphy, 1904, undated
  - Two scrolls of Qing dynasty commendation scrolls to the maternal grandparents of an official named Zeng Wenyu, 1904 (Box 2)
  - Brocade fabric (three pieces), undated (Box 2)
  - A scroll of calligraphy, undated (Box 2)
  - Illustrations from China: Its Scenery, Architecture, Habits, etc., undated (Box 2)
  - One painting and colophon of Wang Xizhi and Wang Xianzhi attributed to Zhao Mengfu of the Yuan dynasty, possibly Liulichang forgery from late Qing dynasty, undated (Box 2)
  - One painting with two horses, undated (Box 2)